South Ostrobothnia, Finland +358 451855522 Amber.pontinen@gmail.com



# **Amber Pöntinen**

Identifying areas of improvement, developing strategies to ameliorate those areas, and thorough implementation of those strategies are three skills that represent my strengths. Where some may see problems, I see challenges that can be conquered. With this mindset and my strong work drive, I strive towards consistent and measurable positive changes in all areas of my life.

My skills and mindset have fuelled the key roles of my career which have centered around data collection & administration. Analyzing this data has allowed me to identify opportunities and challenges and to form strategies to improve them. Recently, this led me to develop a customized Inventory Database Management (IDM) system for Domretor Oy. This IDM tackles the challenges that were being faced with the previous inventory system and focuses on accuracy, efficiency, and improvement. As a certified Full Stack developer, I applied my knowledge of coding and databases to build this system in programs readily available in the office setting; i.e., Microsoft Access and Microsoft Excel.

The challenge and excitement of Front End, Back End and Full Stack Development are indisputable. Writing clean, readable, executable code with semantic meaning has been as rewarding as seeing the ready website. I truly enjoy knowing that as a developer, I will continuously learn new and exciting technologies and techniques! Web development has given me the opportunity to embrace my creative and analytical side at the same time. Plus, the skills that I have gained throughout my career have directly impacted my skills as a developer in a positive way. I bring along experiences with me that help me to work well in teams, communicate efficiently, document projects thoroughly and receive & apply feedback professionally.

Thank you for your consideration!



# **AMBER PÖNTINEN**

FULL STACK DEVELOPER | QUALITY CONTROL ASSISTANT

+358451855522



Amber.pontinen@gmail.com



/in/amberpontinen

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

July 2019 - Present, 3 roles:

Quality Control Assistant, Domretor Oy | Kauhava, Finland Key responsibilities:

- Daily Inspection of the facility, equipment, products, and packaging materials.
- Sample preparation and handling.
- In-house control and documentation monitoring.
- Archive management and improvement.

#### **Current Projects:**

- Inventory Database Management (IDM):
  - I am developing a fully customized bar code driven IDM system which utilizes Microsoft Access, Excel, and Visio.
  - Programed to work directly with the company's ERP to provide a more efficient way for inventory control.
  - This program has passed all preliminary test and is expanding within the company.
- Archive management:
  - When building this program my focus has been easy document retrieval. The documents must be organized in a way that access to those documents is simple and efficient. I have consistently worked to maintain and improve the archive as the company's needs have evolved.

### March 2022 - March 2023

# Employee Trainer & Factory Worker, Domretor Oy | Kauhava, Finland

### **Key responsibilities:**

- I provided training in both English and Finnish.
- I worked directly with new and tenured employees.

# **KEY SKILLS**

- JAVASCRIPT
- REACTJS
- NODE.JS
- EXPRESS
- FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT
- INVENTORY DATABASE MANAGEMENT
- DATABASE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM – SQL & NoSQL
- GIT AND GITHUB
- HTML5 & CSS3
- QUALITY CONTROL
- ARCHIVE MANAGEMENT
- RISK ANALYSIS
- SCHEDULING
- EXPORT

### ATK - SKILLS

- WORD
- EXCEL
- ACCESS
- POWERPOINT
- SHAREPOINT
- VISIO

#### July 2019 - March 2022

# Factory Worker, Domretor Oy | Kauhava, Finland

### **Key responsibilities:**

- Preparation of food products provided by Domretor Oy.
- Packaging of products and preparing of transportation pallets.

#### 2017 - 2018

# Prima Power Oy | Project and Export Assistant

- Project and export assistant. (May September 2018)
- Financial administration assistant. (June August 2017)
- \*Internship: Financial administration and Project assistant (October 2016- May 2017)
- Assistant work, including the handling of sales and transport documentation.
- Scheduling and arranging of exports and imports.
  - \* To see my full work experience, please visit my LinkedIn profile: /in/amberpontinen\*

#### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

- **HACCP Training** | ABC Solutions Oy, 2023
- Full Stack Development Certification | upGrad Knowledge Hut,
   2023
- Digistarttipaketti |SeAMK Seinäjoki University of Applied Science, 2022 (Digital Starter Pack)
- Responsive Web Design Certification | freeCodeCamp, 2022
- Hygiene Passport | Finnish Food Authority, 2020
- Näyttötutkintoon valmistavan koulutuksen osallistumistodistus |
   Sedu Aikuiskoulutus, Liikelaitos, 2017 (Certificate of Participation in Pre Degree-Program)
- Liiketalouden Perustutkinto Merkonomi | SEDU, 2017
   (Vocational Upper Secondary Qualification in Business Administration)
- Osaamisen ovi työelämään ammatillinen koulutus | SEDU,
   2017 (Knowledge's Door to Working Life Vocational Training)
- Uraohjukset Osallistujatodistus (5ov) | B2.1 | SEDU & Centriaammattikorkeakoulu, 2016
- Suomen Kielen ja Kulttuurin Koulutus (42 ov) | B1.1 | Lapuan Kristillinen Opisto, 2014–2015 (Finnish Language and Culture Education)
- Oppilaskuntatoiminta Osallistujatodistus | Lapuan Kristillinen
   Opisto, 2014–2015 (Certificate of Participation in the Student Union)
- Associate of Science AS Business Administration and
   Management, General | Salt Lake Community College, 2013

#### **LANGUAGES**

- ENGLISH: NATIVE
   LANGUAGE
- FINNISH: BUSINESS
   PROFICIENCY

### **CHECK OUT MY REPOS:**

HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/AMBER-LEA-P

#### **AWARDS**

- JUNIOR WORLD
   CHAMPION POWERLIFTER |
   WABDL WORLD
   CHAMPIONSHIPS, 2013
- OPEN WOMEN'S CLASS –
   198S SILVER, | WABDL
   WORLD CHAMPIONSHIPS,
   2013
- OPEN WOMEN'S CLASS –
   198S SILVER | WABDL
   WORLD CHAMPIONSHIPS,
   2012

# **INTERESTS**

- FULL STACK DEVELOPMENT
- SERVERS & NETWORKS
- CYBER SECURITY
- PHOTOGRAPHY
- FIGMA, UI/UX
- VIDEO GAME
   DEVELOPMENT